Guide to the Varian, Inc. Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Records, Accession ARCH-1999-077
  - Prints, Slides, Transparencies, Photo ID Sheets, Subseries 2
    - Sample Processing - A., For Chemical Analysis/Analytichem, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Chromatograph, Gas - Prod., 11/88 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Automated glass-blowing of x-ray tube (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Chromatograph, Gas - Prod., Mfg. Test - W.C. Annual, 11/88 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Manuf. - Clinac, In Manufacturing/Final test, 11/90 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Clinac Assembly Modulator, 11/88 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Clinac - Manufacturing, Production floor, 1986 Annual (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Clinac - M., Manufacturing/Palo Alto, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Clinac Components - M., Testing and Manufacturing, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Sputtering System, 3290 - Manufacturing (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Radiation Manufacturing, 11/88 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Nuclear Magnetic Resonance (NMR) - Prod.- Just In Time/Instrument, 11/88 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Presentation of ESCA Spectrometer to Smithsonian (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Building 1, Varian, Palo Alto (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Building 2, Varian, Palo Alto (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Building 3, Varian, Palo Alto (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Building 4A, Varian, Palo Alto (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Building 4B, Varian, Palo Alto (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Building 4 Complex, Varian, Palo Alto (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Building 5 Complex, Varian, Palo Alto (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Building 5 (Palo Alto Site) (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Building 6, Varian, Palo Alto (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Varian Research Site Photos (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Building 7, Varian, Palo Alto (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Varian, Palo Alto - Various, Aerials (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Historical - Stanford Lab, Russell and Sigurd (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Signing agreement to acquire Einac (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Historical Pictures (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Early Instruments - Historical (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - NMR Historical Photos (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Historical Photos (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Clinac 1000, anniversary 1984 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - 25th Anniversary of an Idea (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Corporate - San Carlos Varian and Einac (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Dorothy Varian (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Varian, Palo Alto - Historical (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - 25th Anniversary - Historical (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - M. Stearns (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Frederick Terman, Board of Directors 1991 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Ralph Kane (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Ted Moreno (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Lou Malter (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Dr. Felix Bloch (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Emmett Cameron (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Ginzton/O'Rourke (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Ginzton/Parker (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Koala-T Photos (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Glen Huffman (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Contest Photos (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Larry Hansen, Varian Sr. VP - Semiconductor Equipment (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - W.W. Eitel, Eimac Co-Founder (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - J.A. McCullough, Eimac Co-Founder (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - George Caryotakis (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Sege/Ginzton (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Sege with various management (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Tom Sege, China trip 1984 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Tom D. Sege at Plants (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Tom D. Sege Historical (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Richard Orth (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Craig Nunan (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - William Hansen (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Ed Ginzton Photos (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Photos: GOC, CTRL staff (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Slides: Art Fuentes de Oca, Damstadt University, Erivar Hayes (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Slides: Hamburg Show - BP, '73 Zug, '73 Maz, '73 Walton, Turin, Misc. bldgs. (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Slides: Products, Applications (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Slides: Historical People (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Photos: Historical People (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - 1979 Shareholders Meeting (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - The Varian Brothers and others (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Misc. Historical Photos (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Misc. Historical Slides (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Ed Ginzton Photos (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Dick Aurelio (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Dick Levy (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - VMS (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Varian, Inc. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - VSEA (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - People - Varian fellows and other scientists/engineers (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Bill Hansen (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Varian Facilities Shots (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Misc. Photos (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Site Photos (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Records, Subseries 3
    - Press Summaries, 1989-1991 (Box 14)
    - Press Summaries, 1992-1995 (Box 15)
    - Press Summaries, 1996-1999 (Box 16)
    - Press Summaries, 1986 (Box 17)
    - Press Summaries 1987 (Box 18)
    - Press Summaries 1988 (Box 19)
    - Annual Reports 1950-1974 (Box 19)
    - Annual Reports 1975-1980 (Box 20)
    - Network 1986-1990 (Box 20)
    - Annual Reports (original issues) 1980-1988 (Box 20)
    - Annual Reports (original issues) 1989-1998 (Box 21)
    - Company Policy binder (Box 21)
    - Varian Overview binder (Box 21)
    - Personnel Roster: January 1954 - July 1956 (Box 22)
    - Manual: Personalized instruction on microwave measurements (Box 22)
    - Manual: Notes on Magnetron Construction, Operation, and Performance, 9/63 (Box 22)
    - Manual: Personalized instruction on Backward-Wave Oscillators (Box 22)
    - Manual: PAMTD Training and Education Resource Manual (Box 22)
    - Manual: Eimac Power Grid Tubes, Quick Reference Catalog (Box 22)
    - Manual: Training Manual for Traveling Wave Tubes (Box 22)
    - Manual: The Klystron (Box 22)
    - Manual: Personalized instruction on basic microwave principles (Box 22)
    - Manual: Introduction to Gyrotrons (Box 22)
    - Manual: On the invention of the Klystron and the founding of Varian Associates (Box 22)
    - Varian History File - Annual Reports, 1949-1952 (Box 23)
    - Varian - Background Information - 1956 (Box 23)
    - Misc. for Varian History Files (Box 23)
    - Misc. Articles (Box 23)
    - Introduction to Gyro Devices (Box 23)
    - Personalized instruction on magnetrons (Box 23)
    - Introduction to coaxial magnetrons (Box 23)
    - Varian in Europa (Box 23)
    - Your Future with Varian (Box 23)
    - Varian Associates Magazine Aug/Sept 1981, vol.26/4 (Box 23)
    - Varian Associates: An Early History (Box 23)
    - The $100 Idea (Box 23)
    - Fred Terman, the Father of Silicon Valley (Box 23)
    - Newsnote, Aug. 29, 1986 (Box 23)
    - News Release, gallium arsenide, May 20, 1985 (Box 23)
    - Interoffice, major EDG programs, Nov. 6, 1986 (Box 23)
    - The New Varian, Phase I: 1981-1982 (Box 23)
    - Varian Turnaround Program, Phase I: Survival, 1981-82 (Box 23)
    - Tom Sege Remarks, Cowen Meeting Feb. 10, 1983 (Box 23)
    - MTD Orientation (Box 23)
    - A Century of Progress, May 1990 (Box 23)
    - Packard, Ginzton, etc. notes (Box 23)
    - Photo of man riding VA-812 on saddle (Box 23)
    - Electronic Business, June 1981 (Box 23)
    - 25th Anniversary, Varian in Europe (Box 23)
    - Concepts of General Management in Varian Associates, by E. Ginzton (Box 23)
    - Customer Presentation/overhead transparencies (Box 23)
    - History of Chairmen and presidents (Box 23)
    - History of Varian (Box 23)
    - Overview of Varian (Box 23)
    - Presentation to the Prudential Technology Conference, 11/12/96 (Box 23)
    - FY96 Year End Review, NY Society of Security Analysts, 11/23/96 (Box 23)
    - FY97 9 months Review for Philadelphia Securities Assoc., 7/23/97 (Box 23)
    - NYC Q3 Review, 7/24/97 (Box 23)
    - Corporate Presentation, NY Society of Security Analysts, 11/3/92 (Box 23)
    - 1998 European Financial Review (Box 24)
    - FY96 Year End Review, NY Society of Security Analysts, 11/23/96 (Box 24)
    - Presentation for European Investors, June 1996 (Box 24)
    - Medical Technology: Past Successes, Present Realities, Challenges (Box 24)
    - FY95 Year End Review, NY Society of Security Analysts, 11/25/95 (Box 24)
    - FY94 Year End Review, NY Society of Security Analysts, 11/26/94 (Box 24)
    - Presentation to the Boston Security Analysts Society, 11/4/93 (Box 24)
    - Annual Meeting Presentation, 2/20/92 (Box 24)
    - Shareholder’s Annual Meeting - Palo Alto Hyatt, 2/18/93 (Box 24)
    - NYSSA Presentation (Box 24)
    - Atlanta, Q1, 1993 (Box 24)
    - NYC Q1 Review, 1/28/93 (Box 24)
    - Atlanta Society of Financial Analysts, 1/27/93 (Box 24)
    - Microwave Power Tube Conference Keynote Address, 5/11/92 (Box 24)
    - NYSSA Presentation, 10/24/91 (Box 24)
    - Annual Shareholders Meeting, 2/92 (Box 24)
    - Varian Communications Plan, Gordon Smith, 11/30/82 (Box 24)
    - Communications Task Force, April 1982 (Box 24)
    - Archives (Box 24)
    - Signatures (Box 24)
    - Books, Magazines (Box 24)
    - Varian Benefits 1998 (Box 24)
    - Times to Remember: The Life of Edward Ginzton (hard & soft cover) (Box 24)
    - Varian: Fifty Years of Innovative Excellence (Box 24)
    - National Geographic, Oct. 1982, vol.162/4 (Box 24)
    - News Releases (Box 24)
    - Articles, Memos (Box 24)
    - Pamphlets: Corporate Objectives, Charitable Gifts (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Klystron Developers - Historical (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Model B Klystron - Historical (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Shareholder's Meeting Award - 1961, Historical (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Varian History (Organization) (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Clippings - 1981 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - E. Ginzton Memorabilia (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Corporate Identity Guide (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - 50th Anniversary of Klystron - press releases (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Varian Cartoons - Stats and original artwork (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Misc. Articles by VA Executives (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Product Info: Klystron (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Personnel Ads (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Varianettes, Book Review Section, Notebook 1957-62 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - 25th Anniversary - Article (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Employee Benefits (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Product Info: General (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Acker, A.E. "How to Speak Radar: Radar Fundamentals for the Marketing Engineer", 1967 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Klystron: History (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Product Info: NMR (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Bomac Co. Catalogs (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Product Info: Satellite Magnometer (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Product Info: Ceramic-Metal Seals (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Product Info: What's New at Varian (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Product Info: Radiation Division (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Product Info: Pumps and Vacuum Products (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - The Development of Microwave Tubes for Radar Transmitters [book], 9/72 (Box 25)
    - The Tall Tree, The story of Palo Alto and its neighbors. Oct. 1955, Dawn of the Electronics Age, Vol. 1/7 (Box 25)
    - The Tall Tree, The story of Palo Alto and its neighbors, May 1958, The first 50 years of electronics research, Vol. 1/9 (Box 25)
    - The Varian Way to be a Gourmet (cookbook) (Box 25)
    - D#1 Biogs.: Heimbucher, Clifford V. (Box 26)
    - Varian, Russell - Collection of articles (Box 26)
    - Varian Assoc. - Last Shareholder's and Board Meeting, Feb. 1999 - photos (Box 26)
    - Ginzton Public Art Project - 1999 (Box 26)
    - SLAC (Box 26)
    - Russell H. Varian Files (assorted talks, etc) (Box 26)
    - V.A. Oral History Records: (Box 26)
    - Oral History Project Index, 1990 (Box 26)
    - Interview with Dr. Edward Ginzton 1990 (Box 26)
    - Chronology, 1948-1969 (Box 26)
    - Oral History Project: Planning (Box 26)
    - Oral History Project: Packard (Box 26)
    - Oral History Project: Proposal: Oral History Association, Inc. (Box 27)
    - Oral History Project: Invoices (Box 27)
    - Oral History Project: Correspondence, historical material, clippings (Box 27)
    - Oral History Project: Interviews (Box 27)
    - Interview transcripts (Box 27)
    - James Arnold, Marvin Chodorow, Edward Ginzton, Craig Nunnan, Cliff Gardner, Ralph Kane, Richard Nelson, James Schoolery, Martin Packard, Armand Staprans, Myrl Stearns, Fred Willimek, Louis Zitelli, Emmet Cameron (Box 27)
    - Assorted files, booklets, slides, photos: (Box 28)
    - Misc. photos and slides (Box 28)
    - Health Safety (Box 28)
    - Intercom (Box 28)
    - MFG Pipeline (Box 28)
    - Industry Week (Box 28)
    - Palo Alto Daily article on Varian (Box 28)
    - Note from Artemas Ginzton following mural dedication (Box 28)
    - Varian Timeline Notes (Box 28)
    - "The Past, Present and Future of the Medical Device Industry" (Box 28)
    - "A Vision for the U.S. Healthcare System: The leveraging of medical device technology" (Box 28)
    - NYSSA Varian Presentation - Nov. 3, 1992 (Box 28)
    - Stockholder's Meeting Announcement - Feb. 21, 1991 (Box 28)
    - Microwave Power Tube Conference Keynote Address - May 11, 1992 (Box 28)
    - Medical Technology: Past Successes, Present Realities, and Future Challenges - Nov. 16, 1993 (Box 28)
    - Remarks from Varian to NYSSA - Nov. 13, 1986 (Box 28)
    - Varian Code of Business Ethics (Box 28)
    - 1994 Application Summary (Box 28)
    - 1998 European Financial Review (Box 28)
    - Presentation to NYSSA - Nov. 2, 1993 (Box 28)
    - FY95 Year End Review - NYSSA - Oct. 25, 1995 (Box 28)
    - Presentation for European Investors - June 1996 (Box 28)
    - 1995 Application for the Malcolm Baldridge National Quality Award (Box 28)
    - Varian Employee Perception Survey (Box 28)
    - The Making of Silicon Valley: A 100-year Renaissance (Box 28)
    - Stanford 100 Years (Box 28)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1968 (Box 28)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1968 (Box 28)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1968 (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
    - Press Releases - 1964-1969 Indices; 1969 Releases (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1969 (Box 29, Folder 4-5)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1972 (Box 29, Folder 6-7)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1973 (Box 30, Folder 1-3)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1974 (Box 30, Folder 4-6)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1975 (Box 30, Folder 7-8)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1976-78 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1976-78 (Box 31, Folder 1-2)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1979-81 (Box 31, Folder 3-5)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1981-82 (Box 31, Folder 6-8)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1982-84 (Box 32, Folder 1-3)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1984-85 (Box 32, Folder 4-6)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1985-86 (Box 32, Folder 7-9)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1985-86 (Box 33, Folder 1-5)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1988 (Box 33, Folder 6-8)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1989 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1989 (Box 34, Folder 1-2)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1/2/90 - 7/10/90 (Box 34, Folder 3-4)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 7/23/90 - 12/31/90 (Box 34, Folder 5-6)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1991 (Box 35, Folder 1-3)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1992 (Box 35, Folder 4-5)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1993 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1993 (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1994 (Box 36, Folder 3-5)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1995 (Box 36, Folder 6-7)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1995 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1996 (Box 37, Folder 2-4)
    - Press Releases with accompanying photos - 1997 (Box 37, Folder 5-6)
    - Press Release Index, 1964-1975 (Box 37, Folder 7-8)
    - Press Release Index, 1976-1994 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Varian Magazine, 1956-1964 (Box 38)
    - Varian Magazine, 1965-1970 (Box 39)
    - Varian Magazine, 1971-1979 (Box 40)
    - Partial index (Box 40)
    - Varian Magazine, 1980-1995 (Box 41)
    - Varian Associates Newsletter, 1949-1956 (Box 42)
    - News-Note, 1953-1965 (Box 42)
    - News-Note, 1966-1973 (Box 43)
    - News-Note, 1974-1981 (Box 44)
    - News-Note, 1982-1991 (Box 45)
    - Varian Video Report Summary (Box 45)
    - Varian Associates oral histories, 6 audiocassette(s) (Box 49)
      Stearns, H. Myrl; Zitelli, Lou
      - Transcripts (Box 46-47)
      - Stearns, H. Myrl, 1989 Oct 30-Nov 1; 4 audiocassette(s) (Box 49)
      - Zitelli, Lou, 1990-04-03 (Box 49)
      - Computer files [5.25" floppy], 7 computer media (Box 49)
    - All Things Considered - NPR, 9/23/93; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 49)
    - 40th Annual Meeting of Shareholders, 1988 Feb; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 49)
    - Dr. Ginzton - Summary, 1963 Jan 4; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 49)
    - Irish Ballads as sung by Russell Varian, 1 phonograph record(s) (Box 49)
      - Irish Ballads as sung by Russell Varian, 1943; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 49)
    - Varian Klystron Press Release, 1987 Sep 29; 1 video reel(s) (1 inch) (Box 49)
    - Slide Modules from Manager's Meeting, 1986 Apr; 1 video reel(s) (1 inch) (Box 49)
    - Ed Ginzton History/Varian, Slide Show transfer, 1984 Mar 13; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 50)
    - Ed Ginzton Tribute, Varian Assoc. slide transfer: Master, 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 50)
    - Varian Orientation, 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 50)
    - Pitt/Conn '85 New Products Review, 1985; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 50)
    - Thomas Sege with Chinese Vice Premier, News 11, SJ, 7/28/85; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 50)
    - Varian Manufacturing Tempe Electronics Center, 12/13/85; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 50)
    - Varian Manufacturing Dub, 12/13/85; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 50)
    - C-Series Clinacs, 1986; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 50)
    - Channel 54 Interview with Ed Ginzton, Varian History, 3/21/8?; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 50)
    - Varian Summer 1987, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 50)
    - Varian Video Report, Fall 1987, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 50)
    - Ed Ginzton, Marvin Chodorow, Meryl Stearns, Tape 1, 3/24/86, 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 51)
    - Ed Ginzton, Marvin Chodorow, Meryl Stearns, Tape 2, 3/24/86, 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 51)
    - Varian Associates Travelling Wave Tube, News 4, SF, 3/26/86, 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 51)
    - Vice Premier Yao at Varian, 5/13/86, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 51)
    - Historical Photos, 5/18/87, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 51)
    - Varian Associates Video Report, Summer 1987, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 51)
    - Varian Fall Video: Ernie/Klystron Room, Ginzton Interview, 8/20/87, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 51)
    - Ernie Klystron Standups, Interview: Ed Ginzton, Fall 1987, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 51)
    - Varian Overview August 1995, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 51)
    - Varian "Innovation Overview" May 1998, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 51)
    - Anniversary Program May 13, 1998, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 51)
    - Varian Video Report, Summer 1988: Protection Master, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 52)
    - Varian Video Report, Ch. 1 & 2 Comp., 7/9/90, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 52)
    - Varian Associates, Selected B-roll footage, July 1990, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 52)
    - Varian Video Report, October 1990, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 52)
    - Varian Video Report, January 1991, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 52)
    - Varian Video Report, April 1991, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 52)
    - Varian Video Report, July 1991, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 52)
    - Varian Video Report, Oct. 1991, Back-up Master, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 52)
    - Varian Exteriors, 11/22/91, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 52)
    - Ginzton Research Center Dedication, Field Master, Jan. 1992, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 52)
    - Varian 50th Anniversary, Tape 1, 5/13/98, 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 52)
    - Varian Quality Workshop, February 1992, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 53)
    - Varian May-June VNR, 3/30/92, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 53)
    - Varian Video Report, November 1992, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 53)
    - Varian Corporate Environmental Affairs: Pursuing Environmental Equality, April 1993, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 53)
    - Varian Video Report, February 1994, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 53)
    - A Tribute to Edward Ginzton on his Retirement, 2/6/95, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 53)
    - Varian Overview, Aug. 1995, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 53)
    - Varian Associates, 1996 Nyssa Talk, 10/23/96, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 53)
    - Varian Corporate Overview, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 53)
    - VPD Recovery Program, The New Varian Cryopump, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 53)
    - Varian Animation, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 53)
    - Varian 50th Anniversary Celebration, 5/22/98, 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 53)
    - Varian Booth Semicon West '97, 1997, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 54)
    - Myrl Stearns, 1/16/98, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 54)
    - Best Practices Book Event, Stanford Faculty Club, 3/26/98, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 54)
    - #2 Varian 50th, interview with Wes Anderson, 4/7/98, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 54)
    - #3 Varian 50th, interview with Wes Anderson, 4/7/98, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 54)
    - #11 Varian 50th, Hansen St. Cags, 4/9/98, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 54)
    - #13 Varian 50th, interview with Gordon Moore, 4/13/98, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 54)
    - Tape 1, Professor Ernst interview, 4/17/98, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 54)
    - Tape 2, Professor Ernst interview and B-roll, 4/17/98, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 54)
    - Tape 3, Ernst visuals, 4/17/98, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 54)
    - Full Frame Ernst interview, audio Ch. 1 and 2 discrete, 4/20/98, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 54)
    - Full Frame Ernst interview and B-roll, audio Ch. 1&2 discrete, 4/20/98, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 54)
    - Full Frame Ernst visuals, audio Ch. 1 and 2 discrete, 4/20/98, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 54)
    - Varian 50th, Myrl Stearns Interview, part 1, 4/21/98, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 54)
    - Varian 50th, Myrl Stearns Interview, part 2, 4/21/98, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 54)
    - Varian 50th, Myrl Stearns Interview, part 3, 4/21/98, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 55)
    - Varian 50th, Myrl Stearns Interview, B-roll, 4/21/98, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 55)
    - Varian 50th, Growth Through Innovation, Edited Master, 5/4/98, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 55)
    - Varian 50th Event, B-roll, 5/13/98, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 55)
    - Varian 50th Anniversary, Rehearsal Tape, 5/13/98, 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 55)
    - Ernst Nobel Prize Home Video, Diana Shaving Head, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 55)
    - Varian Greatest Hits, Edited Master, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 55)
    - Santa Clara Valley Historical Association. Silicon Valley: A 100 Year Renaissance, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 55)
    - Varian World Wide Web Material, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 55)
    - Varian 50th Anniversary, Reel 11, 1 videotape(s) (Beta) (Box 55)
    - Varian Video Report, "World Class Manufacturing", 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 55)
    - Radar Poster Series (Box 56)
    - Misc. Varian Photos (people, sites, products, schematics, etc.) (Box 56)
    - Large photographs of Russell and Sigurd Varian and of the plant, some by Ansel Adams (Box 57)
    - Mounted exhibit items (cartoons, photos) and a few oversize paper items (Box 58)
    - Posters, aerial photograph, and framed items (mostly not photos) (Box 60)
  - Unboxed Oversize Items, Subseries 4
    - Framed Newspaper Clippings: SF Examiner 1/30/39; Stanford Daily 1/30/39; and Palo Alto Times 1/30/39